A Guide to the Papers of Julian Bond, 1897-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series VIII: Family and Personal Papers, including photographs
  - Subseries B: Bond Family Papers
    - Bond Family- Correspondence, 1897-1952 (Box-folder 125:4)
    - Bond Family- Correspondence concerning Family History, 1932-2002 (Box-folder 125:5)
    - Bond Family- History, 1927-2000 (Box-folder 125:6)
    - Bond Family- History, n.d. (Box-folder 125:7)
    - Bond Family- History, n.d. (Box-folder 125:8)
    - Bond Family- History (possibly by Horace Mann Bond), n.d. (Box-folder 125:9)
    - Bond Family- Photographs, 1901-1979 (Box-folder 125:10)
    - Bond Family- Photographs, including ancestors and early photos of Bond's parents and family, 1918-1964 (Box-folder 126:1)
    - Bond Family- Photographs, ca.1969-2002 (Box-folder 126:2)
    - Bond Family- Photographs, ca. 1960-2003 (Box-folder 126:3)
    - Family History- Washington and Browne, 1882-1994, n.d., Some copies of letters. (Box-folder 126:4)
    - Manuscript- Freedom Comes to Isom Wilson, ca. 1935 (Box-folder 126:5)
    - Plays and Short Stories, n.d. (Box-folder 126:6)
- Series IX: Publicity including Newsletters, Press Releases, and News clippings
  - Column-The Way I See It.. ., 1977, n.d. (Box-folder 127:1)
  - Georgia Legislature Newsletters, [1965]- 1973 (Box-folder 127:2)
  - Georgia Legislature Newsletters, 1974- 1977 (Box-folder 127:3)
  - Julian Bond at Large, 1974 (Box-folder 127:4)
  - Julian Bond at Large, 1975 (Box-folder 127:5)
  - Julian Bond at Large, 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 127:6)
  - Letters to the Editor from Julian Bond and Horace M. Bond, 1962, 1967- 2004 (Box-folder 127:7)
  - News clippings, 1960 (Box-folder 127:8)
  - News clippings, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 127:9)
  - News clippings, 1965 (Box-folder 127:10)
  - News clippings, 1966 January-April (Box-folder 127:11)
  - News clippings, 1966 May-December (Box-folder 127:12)
  - News clippings, 1967 (Box-folder 128:1)
  - News clippings, 1968 (Box-folder 128:2)
  - News clippings, 1969 (Box-folder 128:3)
  - News clippings, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 128:4)
  - News clippings, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 128:5)
  - News clippings, 1975 (Box-folder 128:6)
  - News clippings, 1976 (Box-folder 128:7)
  - News clippings, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 128:8)
  - News clippings, ca. 1981-1989 (Box-folder 128:9)
  - News clippings, 1992-2004 (Box-folder 128:10)
  - News clippings, n.d. (Box-folder 128:11)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1961, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 129:1)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1966 January 4-13 (Box-folder 129:2)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1966 January 14-31 (Box-folder 129:3)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1966 February (Box-folder 129:4)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1966 March-December (Box-folder 129:5)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1967 (Box-folder 129:6)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1968 (Box-folder 129:7)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1969 January-June (Box-folder 129:8)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1969 July-October (Box-folder 129:9)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1969 November-December (Box-folder 129:10)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1970 (Box-folder 130:1)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1971 January-August (Box-folder 130:2)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1971 September-December (Box-folder 130:3)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1972 (Box-folder 130:4)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1973 (Box-folder 130:5)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1974 (Box-folder 130:6)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1975 (Box-folder 130:7)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1976 (Box-folder 130:8)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 131:1)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond- Bound Packet given to Bond as Senator, 39th District, 1978 July-1979 May (Box-folder 131:2)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond- Bound Packet given to Bond as Senator, 39th District, 1980 (Box-folder 131:3)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond- Bound Packet given to Bond as Senator, 39th District, 1981 January-June (Box-folder 131:4)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 131:5)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 131:6)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, 1990-2006 (Box-folder 131:7)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, n.d. (Box-folder 131:8)
  - News clippings concerning Julian Bond, n.d. (Box-folder 132:1)
  - News clippings concerning Jimmy Carter, 1970-1976 May (Box-folder 132:2)
  - News clippings concerning Jimmy Carter, 1976 June-August, n.d. (Box-folder 132:3)
  - News clippings concerning John Lewis, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 132:4)
  - News clippings concerning George McGovern, 1972 (Box-folder 132:5)
  - News clippings concerning Morris K. Udall, 1976 (Box-folder 132:6)
  - News clippings concerning Vietnam, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 132:7)
  - News clippings concerning Zimbabwe/Rhodesia, 1979 (Box-folder 132:8)
  - Newspaper columns and Opinion Pieces, including Reviews, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 132:9)
  - Press Releases and Statements, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 132:10)
  - Press Releases and Statements, 1973-1977, 1994, n.d. (Box-folder 132:11)
- Series X: Restricted
  - Campaign- Staff Information, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 133:1)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 133:2)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1972 (Box-folder 133:3)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 133:4)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1976 January-June (Box-folder 133:5)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1976 July-December (Box-folder 133:6)
  - Correspondence- Recommendation/Referrals, 1977 January-September (Box-folder 133:7)
  - Miscellaneous Resumes and Employment Documents, 1969-2005, n.d. (Box-folder 133:8)
  - NAACP- Staff, 1995-2005, n.d. (Box-folder 133:9)
  - Student Examination Books- The American University, Washington, D.C., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 134:1)
  - Student Examination Books- The American University, Washington, D.C., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 134:2)
  - Student Grades and Essays- The American University, Washington, D.C., 1996 (Box-folder 134:3)
  - Student Papers- The American University, Washington, D.C., 1996 (Box-folder 134:4)
- Series XI: Audiovisual Materials
  - Subseries A: VHS
    - The Shadow of Hate, 1995, (2 Copies): Boxed text and video teaching package. (Videocassette 0172 and 0172-a.)
    - The Shadow of Hate, 1995, 1 additional unboxed VHS. (Videocassette 0172-b.)
    - America's Civil Rights Movement, 1992, (2 Copies) boxed text and video (VHS) teaching package. (Videocassette 0173 and Videocassette 0173-a.)
    - PBS Video (VHS): The Great Depression- A Job At Ford's, [1999?], Videocassette 0174.
    - PBS Video (VHS: The Great Depression- The Road To Rock Bottom, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-a.)
  - PBS Video (VHS): The Great Depression- New Deal/New York, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-b.)
  - PBS Video (VHS):The Great Depression- We Have A Plan, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-c.)
  - PBS Video (VHS):The Great Depression- Mean Things Happen, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-d.)
  - PBS Video (VHS):The Great Depression- To Be Somebody, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-e.)
  - PBS Video (VHS): The Great Depression- Arsenal of Democracy, [1999?] (Videocassette 0174-f.)
  - University of Alabama Center for Public Television (VHS): Conscience of a Congressman, n.d. (Videocassette 0175.)
  - University of Alabama Center for Public Television (VHS): The Black Vote: Principles vs. Party, Fa-Sol-La-Mi: The Sounds of Faith, Jonnie Shines: On and On, On Target: W.C. Patton, n.d. (Videocassette 0175-a.)
  - University of Alabama Center for Public Television (VHS): On Target: Ray Charles, On Target: Martin Luther King, On Target: Percy Sledge, On Target: Quilting Bee, n.d. (Videocassette 0175-b.)
  - University of Alabama Center for Public Television (VHS): Where Once We Stood, The Music of Muscle Shoals: A History, n.d. (Videocassette 0175-c.)
  - University of Alabama Center for Public Television (VHS): On Target: Selma, On Target: Lonnie Holley, On Target: Give Us the Ballot, On Target: Clarence Carter, n.d. (Videocassette 0175-d.)
  - Civil Rights #588 National Archives Tape # 1 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176.)
  - Civil Rights # 588 National Archives Tape # 2 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176-a.)
  - Civil Rights # 588 National Archives Tape # 3 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176-b.)
  - Civil Rights # 588 National Archives Tape # 4 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176-c.)
  - Civil Rights # 588 National Archives Tape # 5 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176-d.)
  - Civil Rights # 588 National Archives Tape # 6 (VHS), n.d. (Videocassette 0176-e.)
  - 642A VHS: SNCC, The Abolitionist and The Modern South, 1988 April 14 (Videocassette 0177.)
  - 642B VHS: The Redemptive Community, The Sit Ins, The Freedom Rides, The Birth of SNCC, 1988 April 14 (Videocassette 0177-a.)
  - 642C VHS: The Beginning of the Voter Registration Movement, 1988 April 15 (Videocassette 0177-b.)
  - 642D VHS: The Beginnings of the Voter Registration Movement Part 2, 1988 April 15 (Videocassette 0177-c.)
  - 642E VHS: In The Middle of the Iceberg: The Movement in Mississippi, 1988 April 15 (Videocassette 0177-d.)
  - 642F VHS: Questions from #4, Oh Freedom: The Music of the Movement, The SNCC Women and the Stirrings of Feminism, 1988 April 15 (Videocassette 0177-e.)
  - 642G VHS: The SNCC Women and the Stirrings of Feminism Part 2, 1988 April 15 (Videocassette 0177-f.)
  - 642H VHS: Alabama Bound: Selma and Lowndes County, Black Panther Party, 1988 April 16 (Videocassette 0177-g.)
  - 642I VHS: The Rise and Triumph of Black Power, 1988 April 16 (Videocassette 0177-h.)
  - 642J VHS: SNCC the 1960s and the American Democratic Tradition, 1988 April 16 (Videocassette 0177-i.)
  - VHS (2 Copies): Roy Wilkins: The Right to Dignity, n.d. (Videocassette 0178 and Videocassette 0178-a.)
  - VHS (2 Copies): President Johnson at LBJ Library Civil Rights Symposium 1972, 1972 (Videocassette 0179 and Videocassette 0179-a.)
  - VHS Brotherhood Dinner 2004: To Speak, To Act: The Legacy of Julian Bond, 2004 (Videocassette 0180.)
  - VHS NAACP National Voter Fund 2000: Byrd TV 1, Byrd TV 2, 2000 October (Videocassette 0181.)
  - VHS Bond Video Tape A Photo Tribute to Julian Bond 2002, 2002 July 23 (Videocassette 0182.)
  - VHS: Out of Obscurity, 1999 (Videocassette 0183.)
  - VHS: Mighty Times: The Legacy of Rosa Parks, 2002 (Videocassette 0184.)
  - VHS: Peace Propaganda and the Promised Land, 2003 (Videocassette 0185.)
  - VHS: CNN Presents: The Summer of 64, n.d. (Videocassette 0186.)
  - VHS: The Times and Dreams of Martin Luther King Jr., 1993 (Videocassette 0187.)
  - VHS C-SPAN: Brown v. Board of Education 50th Anniversary Part 1, 2005 (Videocassette 0188.)
  - VHS C-SPAN: Brown v. Board of Education 50th Anniversary Part 2, 2005 (Videocassette 0188-a.)
  - VHS: The Intolerable Burden, 2002 (Videocassette 0189.)
  - VHS: Malcolm X, n.d. (Videocassette 0190.)
  - VHS: CNN Freedom Summer, n.d. (Videocassette 0191.)
  - VHS Guggenheim Productions Shadow of Hate, n.d. (Videocassette 0192.)
  - VHS Part One of Two Video Clips Compiled by Juliette Landphair, 1993-1994 (Videocassette 0193.)
  - VHS: National Voter Fund November 28, 2000, 2000 November 28 (Videocassette 0194.)
  - VHS NAACP National Voter Fund Purged Yet?, 2004 October 11 (Videocassette 0195.)
  - VHS: Montgomery Boycott Makers, 1994 March 23 (Videocassette 0196.)
  - VHS (2 Copies) Du Bois, n.d. (Videocassette 0197,-a.)
  - VHS Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 1, 1997 MarCH 9 (Videocassette 0198.)
  - VHS Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 2, 1997 March 9 (Videocassette 0198-a.)
  - VHS: Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 3, 1997 March 10 (Videocassette 0198-b.)
  - VHS: Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 4, 1997 March 11 (Videocassette 0198-c.)
  - VHS: Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 5, 1997 March 12 (Videocassette 0198-d.)
  - VHS: Newsreels to Nightly News The History Channel Episode 6, 1997 March 13 (Videocassette 0198-e.)
  - VHS (2 Copies) Martin Luther King, Jr. Center King- Montgomery to Memphis Part 1 and 2, n.d. (Videocassette 0199, 0199-a.)
  - VHS The Promised Land Episode 1 Any Place But Here, 1994 November 28 (Videocassette 0200.)
  - VHS The Promised Land Episode 2 Sweet Home Chicago, 1994 November 28 (Videocassette 0200-a.)
  - VHS The Promised Land Episode 3 Standing at the Crossroads, 1994 November 28 (Videocassette 0200-b.)
  - VHS The Promised Land Episode 5 The Walls of Jericho, 1994 November 28 (Videocassette 0200-c.)
  - VHS @Howard Episode #115 Julian Bond, 2002 December 20 (Videocassette 0201.)
  - VHS Interviews with Woolworth Sit-In Participants, n.d. (Videocassette 0202.)
  - VHS News Hour with Jim Lehrer Dave Walker, 1996 June 3 (Videocassette 0203.)
  - VHS This Far by Faith, n.d. (Videocassette 0204.)
  - VHS Julia Agnes Washington 85th Birthday Party, n.d. (Videocassette 0205.)
  - VHS Oh Freedom After While, the Missouri Sharecropper Protest of 1939, n.d. (Videocassette 0206.)
  - Subseries B: CD-ROM/DVD/Computer Disks
    - NAACP National Voter Fund 2000 Campaign, 2000 (Disk 0445.)
    - Barnes Collection Update,, The Kojo Nnamdi Show, American University Radio, 2004 (Disk 0446.)
    - Why Don't We Make It Happen Here: The H. Julian Bond Professorship in Civil Rights Studies, 2007 (Disk 0538.)
    - Harvard University The Civil Rights Project No Child Left Behind Educational and Advocacy Video Series- DVD, n.d. (Disk 0447.)
    - NAACP Unit Network Computer Disks, n.d. (Disk 0448, -a.)
  - Subseries C: Audiocassette Recordings
    - Black Biography Presents Julian Bond, Dr. Kenneth B. Clark, Glory of Timbuktu, Eugene Jacques Bullard Boxed Set, n.d. (Audiocassette 0644, 0644-a.)
    - Malcolm X Grass Roots Speech, 1963 November (Audiocassette 0645.)
    - Radio interview of Julian Bond, Carl B. Stokes, and Gloster Current with Tom Snyder on News Center 4 concerning Governor Jimmy Carter's comments about "ethnic purity" during the 1976 Primary, [1976] (Audiocassette 0647.)
    - American Library Association Let's Celebrate Ethnicity! pre-publication tape sent to Bond as a Speaker/Panelist of the 1976 Centennial Conference, 197[7?] February (Audiocassette 0648.)
    - Mass Meeting for Concerned Citizens The Honorable Julian Bond, Bibleway Church, Columbia, South Carolina, 1988 May 2 (Audiocassette 0649.)
    - Nakawatse Simmons on a micro-audiocassette, 1989 March 2 (Audiocassette 0650.)
    - Taylor Branch on a micro-audiocassette, 1989 April (Audiocassette 0650-a.)
    - Unidentified recording on a micro-audiocassette, n.d. (Audiocassette 0650-b.)
    - Ben Brown on a micro-audiocassette, 1990 May 5 (Audiocassette 0651.)
    - Charlie Cobb on a micro-audiocassette, 1990 July 19 (Audiocassette 0651-a.)
    - Ivanhoe Donaldson on a micro-audiocassette, 1990 August 10 (Audiocassette 0651-b.)
    - 77th Annual Conference, Civil Rights: Then and Now, 1999 (Audiocassette 0652.)
    - B. L[uther] to Julian Bond Fan Mail recording; largely incoherent; accompanied by a clipping of Hunter S. Thompson column dated January 28, 1988, which has been filed with other news clippings, [1988?] February 9 (Audiocassette 0653.)
    - Unidentified Music, n.d. (Audiocassette 0654.)
    - Democratic Convention, San Francisco, 1984 (Audiocassette 0655)
  - Subseries D: Phonodisks
    - Abraham, Martin &John and From Both Sides Now by Dion, 7, 1978, phonodisk, 45 rpm. (Phonodisk 0737.)
    - Flight NAACP 105 and High Ride by Sons of Mississippi, 7, n.d., phonodisk, 45 rpm. (Phonodisk 0738.)
    - There's a Feeling of Love and Where the Sky Meets the Sea two copies, one autographed by artist Rose Weaver to Bond, 7, n.d., phonodisk. (Phonodisk 0739, 0739-a.)
  - Subseries E: Audiotapes
    - Dr. Horace Mann Bond- Lecture on the History of Education, 1962 July 24 (Audiotape 0243.)
    - Morris Udall Campaign Spot Announcements, #3 is by Julian Bond, 7.5 ips, 1976 (Audiotape 0244.)
    - Udall for President, 7.5 ips, [1976] (Audiotape 0245.)
    - Sound Track- Inspiration for Voters, including Aaron Henry, Charles Evers, Julian Bond, Ben Brown, Clarence Mitchell III, the Rev. Walter E. Fauntroy, Jackie Robinson, James Hutchinson, 7.5 ips, n.d. (Audiotape 0246.)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Audiotape 0247.)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Audiotape 0248.)